Breaking News - Making History
Live from Baghdad is a drama, war, tv movie film directed by Mick Jackson.
A group of CNN reporters wrestle with journalistic ethics and the life-and-death perils of reporting during the Gulf War.A
Directors Guild Award-winning movie for director Mick Jackson, starring Michael Keaton and Helena Bonham Carter.
In 1990, CNN was a 24-hour news network in search of a 24-hour story.
They were about to find it in Baghdad.
Veteran CNN producer Robert Wiener and his longtime producing partner
Ingrid Formanek find themselves in Iraq on the eve of war.
Up against the big three networks, Weiner and his team are rebels with a cause, willing to take risks to
get the biggest stories and - unlike their rivals - take them live at a moment's notice.
As Baghdad becomes an inevitable US target, one by one the networks pull
out of the city until only the crew from CNN remains.
With a full-scale war soon to be launched all around them, and CNN ready to broadcast whatever happens 24
hours a day, Wiener and Formanek are about to risk their lives for the story of a lifetime.
Robert Wiener, played by Michael Keaton.
Ingrid Formanek, played by Helena Bonham Carter.
Mark Biello, played by Joshua Leonard.
Judy Parker, played by Lili Taylor.
Naji Al-Hadithi, played by David Suchet.
Peter Arnett, played by Bruce McGill.
Live from Baghdad is a 2002 American war drama
television film directed by Mick Jackson.
The screenplay by Robert Wiener, Richard Chapman,
John Patrick Shanley and Timothy J.
Sexton is based on Wiener's 1992 book.
The film premiered on HBO on December 7, 2002, during
the prelude stage of the Iraq War.
Michael Keaton stars as Wiener, a CNN on-location producer in
Baghdad, Iraq during the Gulf War in 1991.
The film focuses on the news media's (primarily CNN's) coverage of the war.
Fundamentally an action–drama, the characters grapple with the ethics and implications of 24-hour
journalism in the days leading up to and during the United States-led bombing of Baghdad.
The film explores themes of hotel, gulf war, based on
novel or book, war correspondent, journalism.
The tone is emotional.